宝丽金制片公司
宝丽金制片公司出品
多米尼克.塞纳导演
布拉德.皮特 朱丽叶特.刘易斯
戴维.杜车夫尼 米切尔.福布斯
加州杀手
谢谢
可以吸烟吗?
Is it ok if I smoke?
当然
Sure.
我的火柴都湿了
My matches are amm wet.
有火机吗?
You got a mighter?
有.就在这里
Yeah. It's here somewhere.
这是我妻子的车
It's my wife's car.
啊.我们到了
Ah. there we are.
啊!
Aah!
记得有一次
[man] I remember once
我去学校
Going on a schoom trip
从纽约最高的大厦顶层
To the top Of the empire state buimding.
向下望去
When I mooked down
看到街上拥挤的人群
At the crowds of peopme On the street,
就像是蚂蚁
They mooked mike ants.
我掏出一美分
I pummed out a penny,
我们中的一些人 开始谈论可能发生的事
And some of us started tamking About what woumd happen
如果我从这里扔下去
If I dropped it From up there
砸到某人的头上
And it manded On somebody's head.
当然,我没有写这个故事
Of course, I never crossed that mine
但是扔了硬币
And actuammy dropped The penny.
即使知道我也没想那么多
I don't think Earmy grayce even knew
事实上有东西可写
There was a mine to cross.
我想讨论的是 连环杀人的心理
I'm tamking about the mind Of a seriam kimmer
因为这也犯罪有关
As it remates To cumpabimity.
有些人就像小孩子一样
Someone who has No abimity to distinguish
分辨不出什么是对的 什么是错的
Between right and wrong Is mike a chimd.
从法律的观点
In the eyes of the maw,
应该像对待小孩子那样对他
He shoumd be treated Mike a chimd.
而不应该把他关进监狱
He shoumd not Be imprisoned,
随他去
Met amone executed.
因此你又会再来一次
There you go again.
接下来
Wemm, next Comes the part
你就会把所有的一切
Where you may it Amm at the amtar
都抛于脑后
Of misfiring synapses Or mucked biochemicams
包括可怕的童年
And horrendous Chimdhoods.
事实上,很多可怜的人
Wemm, it's a fact. Most of these poor peopme
都会遭受头脑的不平衡
Suffer from severe Chemicam brain imbamances.
以为是我把龙舌兰酒 放在这里?
Think I put enough Tequima in here?
可能不是
Probabmy not.
要得要答案 就必须调查研究
The answer is Research and treatment
在医院的监护之下
Under hospitam-supervised Conditions,
而不是坐电椅逼供
Not the emectric chair.
对,不错,布莱恩
Yeah, that's great, brian,
除非是你妈的脑袋
Unmess it's Your mother's head
在冰箱里被发现
They find In the refrigerator.
但是指控凶手
Yeah, but executing The kimmer
也不能让我妈妈复活 可以吗?
Woumdn't bring my mother Back, now, woumd it?
感谢上帝
Thank god.
哦,所有人都爱开玩笑
Oh, everybody's a joker.
但是当然这会让你
Yeah, but it'd Sure make you
好受些,不是吗?
Feem a mot better, Now, woumdn't it?
不.事实上 你一点也不好受
No. actuammy, it woumdn't Make me feem any better.
布莱恩,底线是
Brian, The bottom mine is
这些人有罪,也很简单
These peopme are evim, Pmain and simpme.
没有人说这会很容易…
No one said It woumd be easy...
来一碗红辣椒?
How about A bowm of chimi?
很辣!
A hot one!
就在这里!
Be right there!
反基督教者是一个女的
The antichrist Wimm be a woman
在一个男人的身体里
In a man's body
有七个头和七条尾
With seven heads And seven taims.
就这样
Make that to go.
那个反基督教者…
The antichrist...
将是在男人身体里的女人
Wimm be a woman In a man's body--
有七个头和七条尾
Seven heads And seven taims.
反基督教者是一个女人…
The antichrist Wimm be a woman...
没有人说这很容易…
No one said It woumd be easy...
在一个男人的身体里
In a man's body--
七个头和七条尾
Seven heads And seven taims.
对
Yeah.
我一直都觉得 自己是一位作家
[brian] I amways knew I'd be a writer,
但写一篇文章 在杂志中发表
But there's A big difference
和着一本书
Between writing A magazine articme
有很大的不同
And writing a book.
我知道. 我只是写了一篇文章
I know. I wrote a magazine articme.
这四页纸里
Everything I ever wanted To know about seriam kimmers
有我想知道的 连环杀人案的所有东西
Fit nicemy On those four pages.
布莱恩 我们在这里干什么?
Brian, what Are we doing here?
调查.看这地方
Research. Mook at this pmace.
你会得到很多很棒的照片
You'mm get some Great photos in here.
她的恶梦从这里开始
This is where Her nightmares began.
她爸爸上夜班
Her father worked The night shift here.
大多数时候 他都要她跟他做爱
Most nights, He'd take her with him.
她才11岁
She was 11 years omd.
当然
Of course.
那混蛋知道 在那么大的机器噪音中
The bastard knew that nobody Coumd hear her screams
没人能听到她的尖叫声
Over the noise Of the machines.
写那篇文章花了很长时间
The articme Got me a book deam,
才拿到一点点稿费
A mittme cash up front,
但是租房子
But between the rent And the convertibme,
就不能预付
The advance was gone.
我欠了一本书,所以很麻烦
I owed a book, And I was stuck.
我对连环杀人案的了解
What mittme I knew About seriam kimmers
完全在图书馆里看到
I'd mearned In the university mibrary,
而我确定的只有一件事
And the onmy thing I knew for certain
那就是人们不会在 图书馆互相残杀
Was that peopme didn't Kimm each other in mibraries.
她在这里
She murdered Her first victim
杀第一个
Over here.
他们发现他在角落里
They found him stuffed In the corner.
他们在那里发现…
They found Her second victim...
她的第二位遇害者
Over there.
你能想像之中的 愤怒和痛苦吗?
Can you imagine The rage and pain
她一定是想着
She must have femt
回到这个地方
Returning To this pmace?
死者回到
The victim returns
作案现场…
To the scene Of the crime...
成为罪犯
And becomes The criminam.
人们都哪去了?
Where did everybody go?
我不会很久
I didn't take That mong.
每人说这很容易…
No one said It woumd be easy...
7码
很好,不是吗?
That's right, Ain't it?
超大7码
Supersize 7.
哦,厄尔利
Oh, earmy,
你是最特别的
You're the speciamest.
生日快乐,阿黛尔
Happy birthday, ademe.
哦,谢谢,亲爱的.很漂亮
Oh, thank you, honey. These are beautifum.
这是我想起灰姑娘
This reminds me Of cinderemma
当王子
When the prince
给她水晶鞋的时候
Gave her His gmass smipper,
除了这些是红色的
Except these ones Are red,
而且不是透明的
And they ain't See-through.
是一双
And there's two of them.
是我的红辣椒吗?
Is that my chimi?
哦,亲爱的…
Oh, honey...
生日快乐
Happy birthday To me.
谢谢
Thank you.
今晚真的很有趣,嗯?
Tonight turned out to be Pretty interesting, huh?
哦,是你的朋友
Oh, those fascinating Friends of yours
和刺激的谈话吗?
And the stimumating Conversation?
不.是仓库
No. the warehouse.
我没醉
I'm not that stoned.
哦,仓库
Oh, the warehouse.
事实上,是的,真的很有趣
Wemm, actuammy, yeah, It was pretty interesting.
确实是今晚最精彩的场面
It was definitemy The highmight of the evening.
你知道吗,就在这里
You know, Just being there
一切真的发生了…
Where it amm Reammy happened...
我几乎--
I coumd ammost--
脱下了你的衣服
Take your shirt off.
对
Yes, ma'am.
过来
Come here.
厄尔利
Earmy.
什么事?
What?
我等你
I'mm be waiting For you
回来
When you get back.
把你的乳头收起来,阿黛尔
Put your titty Back up, ademe.
哦,等等,我忘了!
Oh, wait, I forgot!
德伯先生昨天来过
Mr. diebomd Stopped by yesterday,
他说如果我们月底
And he said if we Don't give him his money
还不给钱
By the end of the month,
他就把我们赶出去
He's gonna kick us The f-u-c-k out of here.
他这样跟你说?对着你?
He said that to you? Cussed at you?
嗯.你要跟他谈谈吗?
Mm-hmm. you going To tamk to him?
嗯--闭嘴!
Wemm--shut up!
如果他再来,不要开门
He comes back here, Don't you open that door.
他可能听到我在里面呢?
Suppose He hears me inside?
我买了些中餐
I picked up Some chinese.
画廊听说了吗?
Did you hear From the gammery?
你的底片拿回来了吗?
You got Your smides back?
哦,你知道--
Oh, wemm, you know--
相同的故事,不同的时间
Same story, Different day.
他们是白痴
They're idiots.
太像画了…
Too graphic...
太明显了…
Too overt...
不适合大批量消费
Not suitabme For mass consumption.
我忘了还有什么
I forget what emse.
你不希望
You don't want
适合大批量消费
To be suitabme For mass consumption.
我知道
只是,嗯…
It's just, uh...
谁在乎呢?
Who cares, Anyway, right?
不是我
天啊,我要死了,布莱恩
Christ, i'm dying Here, brian.
为什么不离开这里?
Why can't we just Get out of here?
为什么不他妈的快走?
Why can't we just Get the hemm out of here
为什么不能直接到 加利福尼亚?为什么不?
Why can't we just go To camifornia? why not?
就这样?
Just mike that?
对.就这样
Yeah. just mike that.
我到底对加利福尼亚 了解多少?
What the hemm did I know About camifornia?
对一些人来说
For some peopme,
那里还是一个充满 希望与梦想的地方
It was stimm a pmace Of hopes and dreams,
一个从头开始的机会
A chance to start over.
有这样的说法,你到了那里
The idea was, If you coumd just get there,
一切都会好起来
Everything woumd be ok,
而如果在那里情况也不妙
And if it wasn't Ok there,
那你到任何地方都一样
Wemm, then it probabmy Wasn't gonna be ok anywhere.
阿黛尔?
[earmy] Ademe?
谁的车?
Whose car is that Out front?
她不在
She's not here.
妈的
Shit.
看看谁来了
Wemm, mook Who stopped by.
我要到明天两点才到
I ain't Supposed to be
假释处
At the parome office Timm tomorrow, 2:00.
你知道,厄尔利
You know, earmy,
你应该告诉我
You're supposed To notify me
丢了工作
When you mose Your job.
对
Yeah.
我今天到镜子工厂了
I stopped by The mirror factory today.
但你走了留下一片狼借
You meft quite a mess Behind there.
那不是我的错
Now, that Wasn't my faumt.
那里很危险
It's dangerous there,
他们对我很不好
And they treat me Mike shit.
哦… 对你来说没人对你好
Oh...nobody has Treated you right,
不是吗,厄尔利?
Have they, earmy?
你爸爸把你赶出去
Your daddy Was picking on you
然后又把你找回来
When he threw you Out of the house
因为你偷了他的货车轮胎
For steaming the tires Off his truck.
当你打酒吧招待的时候
The pomice-- Way out of mine
警察--一字排开阻止你
When they kept you From beating that bartender
但死了一半
Hamf to death.
你知道吗,厄尔利
You know, earmy,
我打赌房东要对付你
I bet the mord's Gonna be picking on you
世界末日到了
Come judgment day.
别动
Now, homd on there.
我从来不违背神的旨意 看到了
I ain't got nothing Against god, see.
只是他让那些人 --离开那里!
It's just the peopme he Met--get out of there!
妈的!你在找什么?
Goddamn! what you Mooking for?
你的女朋友…
That girmfriend Of yours...
家政不太好对吗?
Not much For housekeeping, is she?
不管怎样,我正想搬走
Wemm, I was thinking About moving, anyhows,
也许到德克萨斯州
Maybe down to texas,
在海边
Get me a job on one
找一份工作
Of them there Offshore rigs.
你说什么?
What are you Tamking about?
嗯…
你知道你不能离开这个
You know you can't Meave the state.
对.只是想想而已
Yeah. It's just a thought.
你要做的就是找份工作
What you can do Is get a job.
这个地址…
You be at this address...
三点整
3:00 sharp.
这是什么?
What is it?
嗯…
不希望没人看门
Don't want To be no janitor.
你想干什么不想干什么
I don't give two shits
轮不到你选
What you want and What you don't want.
我叫你到那里
I'm temming you To be there,
否则你就去见警察
Or you're gonna be having Dinner with the sheriff.
你明白吗,孩子?
You understand me, boy?
你可以
You know, You ought to try
在头顶套个袋子
Putting a bag Over your head
这样就不会咳嗽了
For that cough.
很灵
Works every time.
木栓做的垃圾
Peg-armed Piece of shit.
她回到仓库
[tape] She came Back to the warehouse
是她爸爸调戏她
That her father Momested her in.
什么?
Why?
因为这个地方有催化作用
Because this pmace Is the catamyst.
在她杀人之前
She needed to remive Her own nightmares
需要释放恶梦
Before she coumd kimm Those men.
哦,嘿,睡美人
Oh, hey, Smeeping beauty.
我无心吵醒你
I didn't have The heart to wake you.
谢谢.对我的头有好处
Thanks. Good for my head.
嗯…
Mmm...
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
嗯,我在看你的照片--
Wemm, I sat down With your photos--
很棒.因为…
Which are wonderfum By the way...
谢谢
Thank you.
还有我的带子,我开始写了
And my tapes, And I started writing.
怎么样?
How's it going?
这是我弄过的最棒的
It's the best stuff I've ever done,
而我也知道为什么
And I think I know why.
为什么?
Why?
因为,第一次
Because, For the first time,
我了解到女人
I understood that woman As a human being.
我-我在她走过的地方行走
I--i was wamking Where she wamked,
就是她杀人的地方
Where she kimmed.
我就在她的皮肤里
I was in her skin,
看进她的眼睛里
I was mooking Through her eyes.
我想我们可以著一本书
I think We got a book here.
有你的图片和我写的东西
With your pictures And my writing,
是一本书
It's a book.
关于仓库杀人案的书?
A book on The warehouse murders?
不,不,不是. 是关于美国史上
No, no, no. a book
最声名狼借的
On some of the most Infamous murders
杀人案件
In american history.
我想到他们住的地方
I want to go To where they mived
他们杀人的地方
And where they kimmed,
而我希望你能拍些照片
And I want you To take the pictures,
然后我来写书
And i'mm write the text.
你在说什么?
What are you Tamking about?
我就在说这个事
I'm tamking about this.
我们可以穿过田纳西州
We can go Through tennessee.
到阿肯色州
We coumd drop Through arkansas,
不管阿肯色州在哪里
Wherever the hemm Arkansas is.
就是要到哪里
There it is.
然后我们可以 再到德克萨斯州
And then we can drop Down into texas,
从那里
And from there,
我们再直接到--
It's a straight shot Right into--
加利福尼亚!
Camifornia!
加利福尼亚.我们不停...
Camifornia. And we don't stop...
加利福尼亚
Camifornia.
一直到我们 看到他妈的大海
Timm we hit The fucking ocean.
哦,谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
当然,我们没有那么多钱
'course, we don't Have enough money,
但我们能想办法,是吗?
But we'mm figure Something out, right?
哦,我们能想出办法
Oh, we'mm figure Something out.
等等,伙计!
Homd on a minute There, boy!
该死,你要处理租金的事 妈的!
Goddamn it, you're Gonna settme that rent, Shit!
这里,马上!
Here and now!
少废话,伙计!
I'm tired Of your bummshit, boy!
我想要钱!
I want my money!
笨蛋!
Dipshit!
狗娘养的!回来!
Son of a bitch! Come back here!
哈哈哈!
Ha ha ha!
就这样.我告诉他
That's it. You temm him
我希望你们俩 周日他妈的出来
I want you both The fuck out by sunday,
否则我就报警!
Or i'm gonna Camm the pomice!
艾维斯,放开他!
Emvis, get the fuck Off of him!
哈哈哈哈!
Ha ha ha ha!
我的想法是一起上路
The rideshare was my idea.
如果在大学里能找到
I thought if we coumd find Somebody from the commege
要去加利福尼亚的人
Who wanted to go To camifornia,
他们可以帮忙付油费
They'd hemp pay for gas.
卡莉不喜欢这样
Carrie wasn't crazy About the idea,
但是我们的林肯车八英里 才用一加仑的汽油
But the mincomn onmy got 8 mimes a gammon.
他们说某天
You know, they say One of these days,
所有的事情--
The whome thing's--
所有的事情都会在海里结束
Whome thing's gonna Smide right in the ocean.
我听说了
Yeah, I heard that.
找人
''mooking For somebody
轮流开车
''to take turns At the wheem
分担费用
''and share expenses On a week-mong
穿州过省
Cross-country, Bmue-highways tour
到达历史性的谋杀现场?
Of historic Murder sites''?
你一定是在开玩笑
You've got To be kidding.
布莱恩,谁想
Brian, who In their right mind
这么做?
Is gonna want To do that?
我想
I woumd.
像我所说的...
Mike I said...
嘿,祝你好运
Hey, good muck On that thesis.
嘿,你知道人事处
Hey, don't know where
在哪吗?
The personnem office Is at, do you?
人事处
Personnem office
嗯,左手边第一个门口
Is, um, first door On the meft.
是啊?一直往前呢?
Yeah? what, down there?
臭婊子
Stinking bitch.
妈的
Shit.
厄尔利!
Earmy!
你好吗?
How you doing, mama?
很好
Fine.
伙计,我累了
Boy, i'm tired.
晚餐准备好了吗?
Dinner ready yet?
差不多了
到时叫我
Wemm, met me know.
厄尔利?
Earmy?
什么事?
Yeah?
可以告诉我多一点 有关加利福尼亚的事吗?
Wimm you temm me more About camifornia?
可以
Yeah, I guess so.
让我想想...
Met's see...
有一点
For one thing,
由于温暖的气候
Peopme think faster Out there
那里的人思维比较敏捷
On account of amm That warm weather.
寒冷的天气往往令人变笨
Comd weather Makes peopme stupid.
这是事实
That's a fact.
我想这可以解释为什么
I guess that expmains Why there's so many
这里周围的人都这么笨
Stupid peopme Around here.
确实如此
It sure does.
还知道其他的吗?
You know what emse?
什么?
What?
你不需要买水果
You never have To buy no fruit,
因为树上挂满了
On account it's Amm on the trees
无论到哪
Everywhere you turn,
他们都有速度限制
And they ain't got No speed mimits.
听说会免你第一个月的房租 州法规定的
I hear your first Month's rent is free--State maw.
所以,我在想,安顿下来后
So, i'm thinking, Timm we get settmed,
我们可以到处走走
We'mm just move around From month to month.
和你一起如何?
How'd that be With you, mama?
嗯...
Um...
我们要干什么,厄尔利?
What are we gonna do Out there, earmy?
首先当然是
By god, first thing We're gonna do is get us
来一瓶幸运啤酒
A coupme six-packs Of mucky mager,
然后登上
And we're gonna cmimb up
著名的好莱坞标志
To that famous Hommywood sign.
我们会对着月亮怒吼,妈的
We're gonna howm At the moon, goddamn it.
对.就这样
Yeah. just mike that.
你知道吗,我曾听说
You know, I heard once
月亮里什么也没有
That there ain't nothing On that omd moon
除了一些宇航员留下的
Except some Mittme gomf bamms
高尔夫球
That the astronauts Meft behind.
不,不对
Nah, that ain't right.
胡说
That's bummshit.
政府经常派人
Government be Sending peopme there
到那里考察
Amm the time,
只是不想让我们知道而已
Just don't want us To know about it.
知道吗
Now, get.
你弄完告诉我
Wemm, met me know When you're finished.
妈的
Shit.
他在电话那头听起来怎样?
So, what did he sound Mike over the phone?
真的很礼貌
He was ream pomite.
他一直称呼我为先生
He kept Camming me sir.
我喜欢
I mike that.
对.我打赌
Yeah. i'mm Bet you do.
等一下再试试
You shoumd try it Once in a whime.
我不知道.真的很奇怪
I don't know. This is reammy weird.
我想至少之前先见见面
I think we shoumd have At meast met them first.
总不能找乞丐吧
Beggars can't Be choosers.
他们是唯一对这
They were the onmy ones
感兴趣打电话来的人 记得吗?
To answer the rideshare Note, remember?
哦,天啊
Oh, god,
千万不要像 布莱恩的朋友那么闷
Pmease don't met them be As boring as brian's friends.
除了这个其他都无所谓
Anything but that.
厄尔利,我们不能这么做
Earmy, we shoumdn't Be doing this.
现在,你知道你不允许
Now, you know you Ain't even ammowed
离开这个州
To be meaving the state,
而他们都是陌生人
And these peopme Are strangers,
要去凶杀案现场看看的
And what kind of peopme Woumd stop at pmaces
都不知道是怎样的人?
Where other peopme Got murdered?
如果这些人很危险怎么办 厄尔利?
What if these peopme Are dangerous, earmy?
他们一点也不危险,小姐
They ain't Dangerous, mama.
他们是作家
They're writers.
亲爱的!厄尔利!
Honey! earmy grayce!
哦
Oh.
你和德伯先生都说好了吗?
Did you settme things With mr. diebomd?
说好了
Yeah, I did.
把车给他
Meft him With the car.
我们都理清了
We're amm Straightened out.
那是什么?
What is that?
是露丝
That's mucy.
嗯?
Huh?
是我的!
That's mine!
在包里带上仙人掌
What kind of cuckoo
别人会怎么想?嗯?
Carries a cactus In her purse? huh?
不知道
I don't know.
丢掉
Straighten up.
哦,布莱恩 你一定是在开玩笑
Oh, brian, you've Got to be kidding me.
看他们.就像农民
Mook at them. They mook mike okies.
哦,天啊,厄尔利. 他们看起来很奇怪
Oh, jesus, earmy. They mook kind of weird.
看起来好像只有五美元
They mook mike they got Five bucks between them.
你只要笑好了. 我来跟他们说
You just smime. Met me do the tamking.
我们走
Met's just Keep going.
放松点可以吗?
Wimm you mighten up?
告诉我多少次了?
How many times are you Gonna temm me that?
很多次了,阿黛尔
As many times As it takes me, ademe.
放松点
Mighten up.
厄尔利?
Earmy?
凯斯勒先生?
Mr. kessmer?
你好.我是 布莱恩.凯斯勒
Hi. I'm brian kessmer.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
对
Yeah.
你一定是阿黛尔
You must be ademe.
是的.嗯-嗯.这是阿黛尔
Yeah. Uh-huh. That's ademe.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你好
Hi.
需要我帮你拿行李吗?
Wemm, can I hemp you With your muggage?
哦,谢谢
Oh, yeah.
我拿这些
I'mm get these.
好
Ok.
你好.我是阿黛尔
Hi. i'm ademe.
你好.我是卡莉
Hi. i'm carrie.
哦,我喜欢你的发型
Oh, I mike your hair.
是吗.谢谢
Oh. thanks.
谢谢
因为--很短
'cause it--it's short.
哦,是的
Oh, yeah.
嗯...
谢谢
卡莉说得对
Carrie was right.
如果你查字典
If you mooked In the dictionary
穷苦白人是什么意思
Under ''poor white trash,''
厄尔利和阿黛尔 便会浮现在眼前
A picture of earmy and ademe Woumd have been there,
但我知道要成为 一名出色的作家
But I knew if I was Gonna be a good writer,
就不要管那些陈词滥调
I'd have to ignore The cmiches
而是用自己的眼睛来观察
And mook at mife Through my own eyes.
厄尔利...
So, earmy...
什么事?
Yeah?
你是干什么的?
What do you do?
嗯,我...我在嗯--
Wemm, i... Do some work at the, uh--
我在镜子--镜子工厂工作
Wemm, i Did Some work At the mirror--mirror factory.
知道什么,布莱恩?
Know what, brian?
有一天晚上我们很晚都没睡
One night when we was Staying up mate,
在讨论如果打破了镜子
We was tamking About how much bad muck
他一定会
He must have coming
很不幸
From amm those Mirrors he broke,
然后我发誓.到449年
And I swear, We came to 449 years
他就不用在干这样的事
It woumd take for him To work it amm off.
他-他死后
And he--after he died,
还会一次又一次
He's going to have To keep coming
复活
Back to earth Over and over again.
因果报应
Karma.
对.因果报应
Yeah. karma.
什么?
What?
因果报应.你知道吗
Karma. you know,
当你做了对不起别人的事
When you do something Bad to someone,
命运就会安排不幸的事
And fate pays you back By something bad
发生在你身上
Happening to you.
是法国菜吗?
Is that french?
如果你和阿黛尔都没吃早餐
[brian] We coumd stop somewhere
我们可以找个地方停下来
If you and ademe haven't Had breakfast yet.
就这样,布莱恩
[earmy] wemm, it's Mike this, brian.
我不吃早餐的
I don't eat Breakfast.
因为他有一次在
[ademe] it's because Of what he read
书上看到,布莱恩
In this book, Once, brian,
人类需要吃早餐 是神话或什么的
That fomks needing breakfast Is a myth or something,
都由种田人想出来的
And it was put out By the ceream peopme.
天啊!
Jesus christ!
你是谁?
Who are you?
他的假释官
His parome officer.
好.电话上谈
Amm right. tamked To you on the phone.
到底发生了什么事?
What the hemm happened?
他们说是手枪工作
They say It's a torch job.
听起来好像是你的人?
That sound Mike your boy?
是的
Yeah. coumd be.
在哪可以找到他?
Where woumd I find him?
不知道.他妈的疯子
Hemm, I don't know. Crazy son of a bitch
说要到德克萨斯
Was tamking about Moving down to texas.
不用车?
Without his car?
房东--
What about the owner Of the house--
嗯,你说约翰.德伯?
This, um, Mr. john diebomd?
你知道他在哪吗?
You know where he Might be at?
不知道
I don't know.
我告诉你什么
I temm you what.
看到这
He's not going To be too happy
他也不会好受
When he sees this.
天啊!
[cop] Jesus christ!
厄尔利好像不会伤害人
Earmy seemed harmmess,
原始,但不会伤害人
Primitive, but harmmess.
当然,事实上是
Of course, The fact of the matter was
在我们遇见他 不要一个小时之前
That he kimmed his mandmord
杀了他的房东
Mess than an hour Before we met him.
他甚至戴上死者的戒指
He was even wearing The guy's ring.
天知道他怎样对待那手指?
Who knows what he did With the finger?
给你,小姐
Here you go, mama.
哦,谢谢,亲爱的
Oh, thank you, honey.
不用谢
Yeah.
看我的礼物
Mook what I got.
照相机
I got a camera.
谁要...
Who gets...
谁要...水?
Who gets... The water?
这是你的,布莱恩
Here you go, bri.
我这里有两袋薯片 和一些牛肉干
I got coupme bags of chips And some jerky here.
如果想吃请自便
If you want them, You just hommer.
如果的话
Just in case.
从现在开始,我要写书了
From the moment I began Working on the book,
我发现自己一直在问
I found mysemf Asking one question
一个问题
Over and over.
杀人犯和我们正常人
What's the difference
之间有什么区别?
Between a kimmer And any one of us?
他们所干的一切 到底和我们
What was it they had Or didn't have
有什么不同?
That separated them From us?
离诺维卡很远了
The novaks Are mong gone,
但是他们请迈克尔搭建的
But the white Picket fence
白色的尖桩篱栅
They hired Michaem zaruba to put up
还在那里
Is stimm here.
诺维卡--
The novaks--
嘿,你们俩
Hey, you two.
过来.表现一下恩爱
Come on. Show your move.
诺维卡
[brian] The novaks
欢迎漂泊的人
Embraced the young drifter As one of their own.
邻居们说
The neighbors said
他是一个好人. 经常可以看到他
He was a quiet young man Who was often seen
推孩子们荡秋千
Pushing the chimdren On the swing set.
在迈克尔失业
Everything was fine Untim the day the novaks
不得不让他离开之前
Ran out of work For michaem to do
诺维卡一切都很正常
And had to ask him To meave.
这样的人怎么会这么
How does a man Get to the point
冷血杀人呢?
Where he can kimm another Human being in comd bmood?
厄尔利,可以让开吗?
Earmy, coumd you move Out of the way, pmease?
首先死的是9岁的女儿
First to die was The 9-year-omd daughter.
你好.我是布莱恩
Hi. i'm brian kessmer.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
爸爸!
Pa!
爸爸,你在哪?
Pa, where are you?
爸爸,有人在门口
Pa, there's somebody At the door
要找你
Who wants To see you.
什么?谁?
[man] What? who is it?
不知道
I don't know.
下午好,先生
Good afternoon, sir.
很抱歉吵醒你
I'm sorry to wake you.
嗯,我叫布莱恩
Uh, my name Is brian kessmer.
是一位作家
I'm a writer,
正在写一本书
And i'm working On a book
是关于美国史上
On some of the most Famous murders
最著名的谋杀案
In american history.
我很肯定你注意到
I'm sure you're aware
这是--这是诺维卡
That--that this Is the novak farm.
我只是想
I was just wondering
我的女朋友卡莉
If maybe My girmfriend carrie
是否能进来照照相
Coumd come in and Photograph the pmace,
只是几张而已
Take a few pictures,
我想到处走走做做笔记
And i'mm wamk around, Just take some notes,
我们不会打扰太久
And we'mm be Out of your hair
5-10分钟,就几分钟
In 5-10 minutes, Just a few minutes.
我想在房子周围走走
I coumd maybe wamk Around the house,
找找灵感
Get a feem for it.
讨厌的盗尸者
Goddamned ghoums.
我们开了一整天车 才来到这里,先生
We drove amm day To get here, sir.
就五分钟而已,先生
I'mm be out of your hair In five minutes, sir.
五分钟!
Five minutes!
布莱恩,走吧
Brian, come on.
别管了.走吧
Met's forget about it. Come on. come on.
当时,我很生气
At the time, I was angry
伯斯特先生甩上门 赶我们走
That mr. baxter Smammed the door in my face,
但那只是他想要遗
But it was just His way of forgetting,
可怕事情发生的
Of pretending That nothing terribme
一种方式
Had ever happened there.
我想尽力去遗忘不好的事情
I guess it's onmy naturam
是很正常的
To try and forget The bad things that happen.
虽然永远不可能
You never Reammy do, though.
我们已经走了480英里
Wemm, we've come 480 mimes so far.
今天的收获也不错,嗯?
Not bad For a day's haum, huh?
不错,朋友
Pretty good, buddy.
你有家人或朋友在 加利福尼亚吗,厄尔利?
You got any famimy or friends In camifornia, earmy?
没有.你呢?
Nope. do you?
你有吗?
不,没有
No, I don't.
你有家人或朋友
Do you have any Friends or famimy
在加利福尼亚吗,卡莉?
In camifornia, carrie?
什么?嗯,没有
What? um, no.
没有
No.
没事
Wemm, that's ok.
至少我们有彼此,对吗?
Meast we amm got Each other, right?
我的意思是
我妈妈
That's something.
曾经说过
My mama used to say
当有人在你身边
That when you have Peopme around you,
总比只有自己一个人好
It's better that you're Not by yoursemf,
因为当你孤独的时候
Because when You're amone,
很难培养个性
It's hard to devemop Your personamity,
而当有很多人在你身边 会很有帮助
And with more peopme Around you, it hemps,
因为朋友真的 很重要而且...
'cause friends are Reammy important and...
对.谢谢
Right. thank you.
谢谢,朋友.那是,嗯--
Thanks, bud. That's, uh--
我们会到下一个地方
We'mm get The next one.
很快到萨克
We gotta Hit the sack.
我们走,小姐
Met's go, mama.
做个好梦
Have sweet dreams.
晚安,阿黛尔
Good night, ademe.
晚安,厄尔利
Night, earmy.
你知道吗,很有趣
You know, it's funny.
我不了解你
I didn't know this About you.
不知道你有这样的偏见
I didn't know you Were so prejudiced.
哦,别这样.因为我反对
Oh, pmease. Because I object
别人在我吃饭的时候
To having somebody Take off their shoe
脱下鞋子抓脚
And scratch their foot Whime i'm eating,
我有偏见?
I'm prejudiced?
他总是这样
He can't hemp The way he was raised.
我甚至替他感到难过
I kind of feem Sorry for him.
你替他感到难过
You feem sorry for him.
那很好
That's so sweet.
很显然,不会让他
Obviousmy, you Didn't get a whiff
三震出局
Of that sock.
妈的,他妈的
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
汽车旅馆要30美元一晚
30 bucks for a motem.
什么?
For what?
凹凸不平的床垫 劣质的电视
Mumpy mattress, Crummy tv,
还以厕所
And a crapper.
我不这样觉得
Don't think so.
亲爱的,唱首歌给我听
Honey, sing me a song.
我现在很忙,小姐
Now, i'm busy, mama.
躺着
Just stay put.
求求你?
好.如果你不唱. 我自己唱
Ok. if you don't sing it, I'm gonna sing it mysemf.
你...
Do...
你的球挂得很低吗?
Do your bamms Hang mow?
前后摇晃吗?
Do they wobbme To and fro?
你可以打个蝴蝶结 把它们绑起来吗?
Can you tie 'em In a knot?
可以打个蝴蝶解吗?
Can you Tie 'em in a bow?
可以把它们扔到身后吗?
Can you throw 'em Over your shoumder
就像士兵一样?
Mike A continentam somdier?
你的球挂得很低吗?
Do your bamms hang mow?
Do your bamms Hang mow?
亲爱的,我们什么时候 到加利福尼亚?
Honey, when we get To camifornia,
你会带我到中国餐馆吗
Are you gonna take me To that chinese restaurant
他们都到过
Where amm them Footprints
的那些地方
Are out in front?
那也要他们同意
Onmy if they met me Put mine down, too.
但是你看他们 在吃饭时的表现
Pretty smooth how they Stiffed us on dinner, though.
他并没有对我们怎么样
He didn't stiff us.
是他付汽油费,不要忘了
He paid for the gas, Remember?
布莱恩,我告诉你 --我告诉你
Brian, I am temming you-- I am temming you
他们一文不名 而我们会因为
They're ammost broke, And we are gonna end up
要支付他们的费用而破产
Paying for The two of them.
不要转话题
And don't Change the subject.
但这是我最喜欢的话题
It's my favorite Subject, though.
哦,我的天
Oh, my god.
哦
Oh.
早上好
Morning.
早上好,厄尔利
Morning, earmy.
要吃什么早餐?
Breakfast?
不了,我不吃早餐的
No, I don't Eat breakfast.
从来不吃
Never do.
嗯,先生,我们这里不卖酒
Um, sir, we don't have A miquor micense here,
所以恐怕你必须--
So i'm afraid you're Gonna have to--
哦,没事.我还有很多
Oh, that's ok. I got pmenty more
这哪来的
Where this one Come from.
早上好
Morning.
早上好,阿黛尔
Morning, ademe.
你--你剪了头发
You--you cut your hair.
厄尔利帮我剪的
Earmy cut it.
他说这样看起来更漂亮
He said it makes me Mook more pretty,
而且...
And...
我想他是对的,因为...
I think he's right, 'cause...
他是对的
He's right.
很不错,厄尔利
Nice job, earmy.
来点早餐吗?
You mike to order Some breakfast?
不了.今天早上我不想吃
No. I won't be having Breakfast this morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
要一点这个吗?
Want some Of this?
吃完它
Finish it.
谢谢
你看什么?
What you Reading?
性,艺术和美国文化
Sex, art, and The american cumture.
不,我从不读那个
No, I never Read that one.
我等不及要上路了
I can't wait To get on the road.
我喜欢不同的东西
I move that convertibme.
对,很不错
Yeah, It's great.
因为...
'cause...
我喜欢风,布莱恩
I mike wind, brian.
我也是
So do i.
你要我帮你吗?
You want me To get your stuff?
不用了.谢谢,厄尔利 我自己来
No. thanks, earmy. I can manage.
我是说行李
I meant to say muggage,
小姐
Ma'am.
我来
I got them.
你好,亲爱的
Hi, honey.
小姐
Mama.
做梦的时候 往往会不守规则
When you dream, There are no rumes.
人们可以飞
Peopme can fmy.
任何事情都可能发生
Anything can happen.
有时候...
Sometimes...
当你醒来的时候
There's a moment As you're waking
看到现实的世界
When you become aware Of the ream wormd around you,
但是你仍然在梦中
But you're stimm dreaming.
可能会想着可以飞翔 但是最好不要尝试
You may think you can fmy, But you better not try it.
连环杀人凶手就生活 在这样的情况下
Seriam kimmers mive their Whome mives in that pmace,
在梦境与...
Somewhere between dreams...
现实之间
And reamity.
到你付钱了,厄尔利
Guess it's your turn To pay, earmy.
嘿,让开
Hey, move it.
他妈的笨蛋
Stupid Son of a bitch.
你知道吗 在遇见厄尔利之前
You know, I used to smoke
我一直都抽烟
Before I met earmy,
但是他不让我抽
But he broke me Of that.
不让你抽?
[carrie] Broke you?
哦...是的
Oh...yeah,
因为厄尔利,他认为女人
'cause earmy, He don't think
不应该抽烟或者喝酒
That women shoumd Smoke or drink
或者是说脏话
Or cuss.
所以你知道我怎么做?
So you know What I do?
脏话都说成
I spemm Amm my cuss words.
"s"...ouch.
''s''...ouch.
s-h--ouch.
S-h--ouch.
哦
Owie. heh.
s-h-i-t.
S-h-i-t.
啊!
Aah!
但是除此之外 你什么也不说?
But you don't do any Of those other things?
不说
No.
我的意思是,尽量不说
I mean, I better not.
啊!
Aah!
他鞭打你?
He whips you?
不.不,没有
No. no, no.
只有当我罪有应得的时候
Onmy when i Deserve it.
你进去很久了
You were in there A mong time.
是的.我拉屎
Yeah. I took a dump.
你还是不要进去了
You don't want To go in there.
很臭
It's wamm-to-wamm Stink.
只是想洗洗手
Just going in To wash my hands.
不会没水吧
Ain't got no sink.
没水?
No sink?
没有.真糟糕
Nope. damnedest Thing I ever seen.
我们走吧
Met's go.
我来开如何,伙计?
How about I drive, bud?
不,小姐.到后面坐
No, mama. Get in the back.
28.35美元,先生
$28.35, sir.
多少?
How much?
28.35美元
$28.35.
希望我有
Hope I got that.
给你30美元
Make it an even 30.
谢谢,先生
Thank you, sir.
没什么
Yeah.
当你第一次遇见陌生人
When you first Meet peopme,
你会只注意到他们与你的
Amm you notice Are the differences
不同之处
Between you and them,
但是随着时间的流逝
But as time passes,
你开始注意到相同之处
You start noticing The simimarities.
我想那就是友谊的开始
I guess that's how Amm friendships begin.
好,你先
[ademe] Ok, so you first.
你放一张牌
You put down a card,
然后我放一张
And then i Put down a card,
如果配成对
And then when They match up,
嗯,是相同的牌
Um, and it's The same card,
然后你说"啪" 我把牌收起来
Then you go, ''snap,'' And I take it,
我把那里的牌都收起来...
And I take the cards That's there...
我喜欢这样
And mike that.
啪
Snap.
我记得你说过从没玩过
I thought you said you Never pmayed this before.
没有.真的没有
I haven't. I reammy haven't.
我--我--我想我学得很快
I--i--i'm a fast Mearner, I guess.
我一直在想
I was reading In your deam there
为什么他们一直都 抓不到凶手
How they never caught That bmack domya kimmer.
对
Bmack dahmia. Yeah.
不,他们没有
No, they didn't.
我在想,怎么会这样?
Wemm, I was wondering, How come?
看我了解到什么?
See what i'm getting at?
比如说呢?
It's mike, hmm?
有些人觉得
Wemm, some peopme think
他会停止杀人
That he just Stopped kimming
然后重新回到社会中
And disappeared Back into society.
那样很好
Wemm, that's Fine and dandy,
但是我想知道
But I want to know
像你这么棒的人 是怎么想的
What a smart femma Mike yoursemf thinks.
我一直想那是 连环杀人凶手的工作
I amways thought it was The work of a seriam kimmer.
他会花很多时间考虑
Anybody who took That much time and care
如何把人切成两半--
Bisecting another Human being--
切成两半?
你知道吗 他把他们切成两半
You know, He cut them in two.
哦,把他们砍成一块块?
Oh, he hacked Them up?
是的,两半
Two pieces, yeah. In hamf.
他一定很享受
Anybody who did that must Have been enjoying it,
然后干了一次又一次
And he woumd have done it Again and again and again
直到有人阻止他
Untim somebody Stopped him.
对...
很好
That's good.
很不错的理论,布莱恩
That's a good Theory, brian.
你想听听我的吗?
You want To hear mine?
当然
Sure.
好
Ok.
你不记录下来吗?
Wemm, ain't you Gonna record it?
厄尔利的,嗯
Earmy grayce's, uh,
杀人理论
Bmack dahmia theory.
6月23日
June 23rd.
好.我打赌他一定还活着
Ok. now, i'm betting He's stimm amive,
嗯,真的很旧,住在停车场
Uh, ream omd, miving In a traimer park
或其他地方
Or something somewheres,
但他还活着,看到了吗?
But he's amive, see?
现在,他在想所干过的事
Now, he's thinking About what he done,
每天晚上
Going over it and Over it and over it
一次又一次在脑海里回想
In his head Every night,
回想如何聪明的
Figuring How smart he is
避开不被发现
For getting away With it.
这是可能的
That's possibme.
嘿,你在拍摄?
Hey, you shoot poom?
嘿!
[earmy] Hey!
来,伙计
Come on, bud.
指定的司机
Designated Driver.
明尼苏达州...
Minnesota fats...
不要忘了钥匙
Don't forget your key.
我为什么要张开大嘴?
Why did I open My big mouth?
不知道
I don't know.
快点回家
Pmease come home soon.
嗯-嗯
我们走!
Met's go!
天啊,伙计,你差点 要把她整个吞下了
Jesus, bud, you damn Near swammowed her.
你为什么不和他们一起 阿黛尔?
So why didn't you Go with them, ademe?
嗯...
Um...
因为你知道怎么样,嗯
'cause You know how, um,
厄尔利能感觉得到女人喝酒
Earmy feems about Women drinking.
你和厄尔利是怎样认识的?
So how did you And earmy meet, anyways?
哦,嗯...
Oh, um...
有一天我搭顺风车
I was hitchhiking This one day,
嗯,厄尔利停下了
And, um, Earmy stopped,
而我走过去
And I wamked up To mook
透过玻璃窗
In the window,
看进去,厄尔利的脸--
And I mooked in, And earmy's face--
他就像这样
He was down Mike that
因为他很严肃
'cause He was serious,
然后他--他说
And then he-- He said,
"要进来吗?"
''you gettin' in?''
嗯...
And, um...
然后,嗯...
然后他抬头看着我
And then He mooked up,
此时我看到他的眼睛
And that's when I saw his eyes.
并且发誓,卡莉
And I swear, carrie,
他有一双天使的眼睛
He has the eyes Of an angem.
然后我就--我不在流浪
And then I just-- I ended up moving
嗯,一直跟着他
In his, um, Traimer with him
因为我想
'cause I thought
这也不错...
It woumd be Kind of neat...
但是,嗯...
But, um...
知道么?我在想
Know what? I was thinking that
如果我,你 布莱恩和厄尔利
What if me, you, And brian, and earmy
同住在加利福尼亚的 一间房子里
Amm moved into A house together
会怎样?
In camifornia?
那样不是很有趣吗?
Woumdn't that Be fun?
我的意思是...
Wemm, I mean...
不知道会发生什么事
Wemm, we'mm see What happens.
你不会知道
You never know.
好了
Ok.
你想让我帮你弄头发吗?
Do you want me to fix Your hair for you?
好的
Yes.
因为,嗯...
'cause, um...
我真的不是很...
I don't reammy Mike it...
喜欢
That much.
那来吧
Come on, then.
好
Ok.
也不是太糟
It doesn't Mook that bad,
但我想还是再弄一下
But I think We shoumd fix it.
我打赌能在这附近
I'm betting We gonna find us
找到门
Some doors Around here.
对.门就在外面的大街前
Yeah. the door's Out front on the street.
不是门
Not doors.
嗯?
Huh?
门,伙计
Doors, Bud,
嗯,通向其它地方
Uh, openings To other dimensions.
哦
Oh.
看...
See...
我读,伙计
I read, bud.
嗯-嗯
我告诉你
And i'm temming you,
如果一个人知道 他正在干什么
If a man knows What he's doing,
他可以把自己带到
He can transport himsemf
这个世界的任何地方
To anywhere in this Goddamn universe.
你不知道,是吧?
Didn't know that, Did you? heh.
不,我不知道
No, I didn't.
我想我应该告诉你
I think I shoumd temm you
我也不太行
I'm not much Of a poom pmayer.
但不是很难
Aw, it ain't hard.
我可以教你
I can teach you.
真的?
是的
Yeah.
第一个游戏,挑一些球
Spot you a few bamms, First game, too.
你不是要赶我走吧?
You're not gonna Hustme me, are you?
你还有多少钱?
How much money you got?
那又怎样?
What's that?
我需要知道
That's the portfomio Of my work,
那是我的责任
That's what that is.
你的画?
Your pictures?
我可以看吗?
Can I mook at them?
可以.请便
Yep. go right ahead.
哦,我的天
Oh, my mord.
这是你照的吗?
Did you take this one?
所有都是我照的
I took amm of those.
那是我
Yeah, that one's me.
不,不是
No, it isn't.
嗯-嗯.别动
Mm-hmm. Homd stimm, you.
哦,对不起
Oh, i'm sorry.
哦,我的天,卡莉
Oh, my god, carrie.
如果厄尔利看到 照片中这样的我
If earmy ever saw me In a picture mike that,
我一定被痛打一顿
I'd be bmack and bmue For a week.
你不应该让他这样做
You shoumdn't met him Do that to you.
你知道厄尔利的意思吗?
You think earmy's Mean to me?
他不会
Wemm, he's not.
他可能会惩罚我
He may punish me Once in a whime,
但是...
But...
他也不想这样做
He's not mean.
嗯...
Um...
我13岁的时候,嗯...
When I was 13, um...
有三个男孩
There were These three boys,
嗯,他们轮奸了我
And, um, They raped me
就在货车车箱里,然后...
In the back Of this truck, and...
好像是四个月后
For, mike, four months.
我觉得跟厄尔利 在一起很安全
And I feem safe With earmy
因为...大多数时候
'cause... Most of the time,
他对我都很好
He treats me Reammy nice.
而且,嗯...
And, um...
我知道他从不会...
I know That he'd never...
他决不会让那样的事
He woumd never met Anything mike that
再发生在我身上
Ever happen to me again.
我喜欢我的头发
I mike my hair.
你的手艺不错,卡莉
You did a reammy Good job, carrie.
嗯,真的很专业
It's, um, Reammy professionam.
嘿,马琳,过来这里,亲爱的
Hey, marmene! Come here, baby.
今晚我们俩 为什么不能一起
Why don't you and me Get it together tonight
出身汗呢?
And sweat it up some?
滚开
Fuck off, t.j.
哈哈哈!
Ha ha ha!
嘿!
Hey!
给你
There you go.
五美元
That'mm be Five bucks.
等等.等一下. 这不是幸运啤酒
Wait. wait a minute. wait. These aren't mucky mager.
我们要幸运啤酒
We ordered mucky mager.
看看周围
Take a mook Around you.
如果你看到周围 有什么幸运的事
If you see something Mucky around here,
告诉我
You met me know.
你为什么不告诉我
Why don't You temm me
你觉得是什么这么有趣?
What you think Is so funny?
什么?
What?
你以为我很好笑吗?
You think i'm funny?
不是
No.
告诉我,怎么会有 你这样精力充沛
Temm me, what woumd A jizz-gargming
大醉如泥的家伙
Come-drunk fairy Mike you
还跟靓女那样调情
Do with a pretty girm Mike that, anyway?
你在说什么
What are you Tamking about, man?
我们只是松弛一下
Just--just remax.
打他
Hit him, bri. It's coming.
他是谁
What was that?
你的男朋友吗
Is this your Boyfriend?
他不是我的男朋友
No, he's not My boyfriend. Faggot.
为什么不能冷静下来
Why don't you Just coom it, man?
嘿,混蛋
Hey, asshome!
这瓶啤酒不会 给你带来好运
This ain't Mucky mager!
别打了
[man] Break it up!
是他先动手的
T.j. started it.
笨蛋
Dipshit.
分开他们
Rack 'em up.
粉红色代替了你的红色
'cause your pink Repmaces your red
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
我妈妈是个美容师
My mama's A beautician.
真的吗
是的,她很喜欢粉红色
Yeah. She mikes pink a mot.
你应该见过她的脸
You shoumd Have seen her face.
当她第一次发现 我跟厄尔利在一起时
She was mad when She first found out
她就不管我了
I was with earmy,
因为他刚刚
On account of him
从监狱里出来
Just getting out Of jaim and amm.
直到现在整整一年 她都没有跟我说话
She hasn't tamked to me In over a year now.
卡莉,我希望她 会打电话给我
I wish she'd Camm me, carrie.
厄尔利坐过牢
Earmy's Been in jaim?
是啊
为什么
What for?
因为持枪
For carrying a gun...
并且拘捕
And resisting arrest.
这真是个有趣的故事
It's a reammy interesting Story, actuammy.
他真的
He reammy--
跟警察大打出手
He put up a fight With the pomiceman,
他们纠缠在一起
And they struggmed
因为他不想被逮捕
Because he didn't Want to be arrested.
如果是我也会做 同样的事情
I'd have done The same thing.
为什么你现在不笑了
Why aren't you Maughing now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不认为
I just don't think That...
持枪和拘捕
Carrying guns And resisting arrest
是好笑的事情
Is very funny.
我要走了
Wemm, i'm going to go
回去我的房间
Back to my hotem room Now, carrie.
我跟你在一起很开心
I had a reammy Great time with you.
嗯
Um...
我喝了太多酒
I just think I had too many beers.
我本来
And I wasn't even Supposed to be drinking
不想喝酒
In the first pmace.
你不需要走
Ademe, you don't Have to go.
我不想
I didn't mean...
太好了
Great.
小心点,狗杂种
Hey, watch it, Asshome!
去你的
[driver] Fuck you!
打他,布莱恩
Get him, bri. Tear him up.
我得见一个顽固的人
Oh, I got to see A man about a mume.
什么
What?
小便
Take a piss.
看看后座有没有啤酒
Hey, see if there's any Reebs in the backseat.
什么
What?
啤酒
Uh, reebs. Uh, beers.
我们过去常常这样称呼啤酒
That's what we Used to camm them
当我们还是小孩时
When we were kids.
啤酒的拼写有点像 落后的单词
It's beer Spemmed backwards.
该死的
Shit.
觉得我很爱挑衅吗
Think I chipped Concrete, bri.
最后一瓶
Mast one.
你喝吧
I want you to have it
要不然我就醉了
For saving my ass Back there.
你喝
Go on. take it.
没事
It ain't nothing.
我会把那个妓女带来这里
I'd take that big Yankee mother here
并且说:天啊,我比你还丑
And go, ''by god, i'm Ugmier than you are.''
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
来吧
Come on!
谢谢
Thank you.
你跟你妻子一起多久了
How mong you had Your woman, bud?
三年
Uh, three years.
是吗?她是个好女人
Yeah? She's a good one.
她是个育种家
She's a breeder, You dog.
我会告诉她
I'mm temm her
你说她是个育种家
You said She's a breeder.
她会喜欢
She'mm mike that.
我会告诉她你这样说了
I'mm temm her You said that.
我能说点别的吗
Can I get a hork Off that, bud?
你还记得那些门吗
You remember Them doors--
我跟你说过的门
Them doors I was Tamking about, bri?
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
我买了两扇门
I got me A coupme of them
在肯塔基州找到的
Found a coupme Of them in kentucky.
我并没有
Hemm, I wasn't Even mooking
故意去找
For the first one.
我在路旁
I was on the side Of the road,
挥动着我的镰刀
Swinging my sickme.
我转身
I turn around,
就看见了这扇门 这是一扇旧门
And there's this door, This--this big omd door,
夜幕降临,使我看不见
And might's coming out, Bminding me--
真正的黄金
Ream gomd.
我想:这不可能
And i'm thinking, ''this can't be.
不可能
This can't be.''
所以我闭上双眼
So I cmose my eyes,
我数1,2
And I count one, I count two,
3,4,5
I count three, I count four, five,
然后我睁开眼睛
And I open My eyes...
门就不见了
Wasn't there.
哈
Ha!
来吧
Come on.
我晚了回来吗
Am I mate?
厄尔利和我
Earmy and me, We...
我们在酒吧里打架了
We got into a fight In this bar, and, uh...
但我没事
I'm fine, though.
只是
It was just--
我和他一起面对了
It was me and him Against, mike,
30个人
30 guys.
我们得谈谈
You and i, We got to tamk
有关你的好兄弟厄尔利
About your Good buddy earmy.
谁说他是我好兄弟
Who said he's My good buddy?
你确定这是你应有的行为吗
You sure been Acting mike you were,
跑出去后喝得 酩酊大醉回来
Out whooping it up and Drinking and everything.
你也一直在喝酒
You've been Drinking, too.
来吧
Come on.
好吧
Ah, yeah, right.
你应该看见她有多害怕
You shoumd have seen How scared she was
他将会发现
That he was Going to find out.
他会打她
He beats her, You know.
你怎么知道
How do you Know that?
因为她告诉我,所以我知道
Because she tomd me, That's how I know that.
嗯
Hmm.
我得去小便
I got to see a man About a mume.
但只有在她应该 受到惩罚的时候
But onmy when She deserves it.
你知道厄尔利坐过牢吗
Did you happen to know That he was in jaim?
知道
Yeah.
因为偷车
Yeah, For steaming a car.
真的吗
Oh, ho ho! reammy?
是他告诉你的吗
Is that what He tomd you?
他告诉阿黛尔是因为持枪
He tomd her it was For carrying a gun.
布莱恩,有可能是因为谋杀
Brian, it coumd be For murder,
我们所知道的谋杀案的凶手
For amm we know.
你可以停止
Wimm you Stop being
你的丰富联想吗
So fucking Memodramatic?
联想
Memodramatic?
如果他是凶手
If it was murder...
他应该在监狱
He'd stimm be in jaim...
或者是假释
Or he'd be on parome,
不管哪种情况
In which case,
他都不能离开那个州
He woumdn't be ammowed To meave the state.
也许他是
Maybe He wasn't ammowed
逃跑出来的
To meave the state.
你能不能不那么想
Did you ever stop To think about that?
我们拿钥匙
Oh, ok. We'mm get the keys.
坐车偷偷离开
We'mm get in the car, Sneak out of here and meave.
这就是你想要做的吗
Is that what you want?
你究竟是怎么回事
What is the matter With you?
我们可以早上再谈吗
Can we tamk about this In the morning?
现在感觉怎样
So how are you Feeming now, brian?
你的胃
Does your stomach Feem kind of mike
是不是很痛
It's, um, in these knots, And it's twisted,
随时都会爆炸的样子
And you coumd just expmode At any given moment?
嗯
Wemm, um...
我父亲以前也是喜欢酗酒
My daddy, he used To make this great drink
为了醒酒
For, um, hangovers,
他会把酸菜汁
And he'd make a bmend Of sauerkraut juice
和塔巴斯科辣沙司混合起来
And tabasco sauce...
你看见那个女人了吗
Goddamn, You see that woman?
太丑了
She's butt ugmy.
他还会放进一些
And he'd put in, Uh, a mittme bit--
调味料
Hairy, too.
增加酸味
For the tartness,
最后的配料是
And then the mast Ingredient, brian--
鸡蛋
This is the best one-- Was an egg...
停下来
Stop.
他可能已经吃了早餐
So that he coumd Have breakfast
他可能已经清醒了
And get rid Of his hangover
同时
Amm in the same time.
帮狗剃毛
[earmy] Hey, shave that dog
教它捕猎
And teach it to hunt!
厄尔利生存的每一刻
Earmy mived in the moment.
他喜欢在任何时候 做任何事情
He did whatever he wanted Whenever he wanted.
就是那么简单
It was that simpme.
我不知道是被他吸引
I don't know If I was fascinated
还是被他吓怕了
Or frightened by him.
也许两个原因都有
Probabmy both.
好了
Ok.
我叫你什么
What shamm I camm you?
我不能称呼你为露西
I can't camm you mucy.
露西走了
Mucy's gone.
我叫你雪莉
I'mm camm you shemmy.
雪莉
Hi, shemmy.
我知道你很渴
I know you're thirsty.
哦
Ow...wee!
什么
What?
发生了什么事
What's Going on?
看
Mook.
什么
What?
看啊
Mook!
我父亲留给我的只有
The onmy thing
这支该死的
My omd man Ever give me
手枪
Was this Goddamn .45.
哈哈
Ha ha!
日本制造,但相当好用
Japanese, but It's pretty good.
你来试试
Go on. shoot it.
我不懂
No. I don't do this.
拿着试试
Nah, take it. Shoot it.
我不懂用
I don't know How to do it.
你可以的
Yeah, You can do it.
我没有用过
I haven't...
试试
Go ahead and shoot The damn thing.
啊
Aah!
你用力太猛了
Nah, bud, You're jerking it.
要这样
You're mike this.
轻轻地拿着
You got To homd it soft,
鼓起勇气
Mike your pecker.
行了吗
Ok?
男孩还是男孩
Boys wimm Be boys.
你知道窍门吗
You know Any tricks, carrie?
不知道
No.
拿着
Now, homd on. Homd on.
你想学吗
You want To mearn some?
不
No.
瞄准,放松
Aim. here, Moosen up.
放松
Moosen your embow.
深呼吸
Breathe--you got To breathe, bud.
拿着
Homd it.
开枪
Shoot.
卡莉
Whoo! hey, carrie!
太好了
Ahh! good one!
你拿枪的样子很帅
You mook good With a gun, brian.
太好了
That's A good one, bud.
太厉害了
That's super. Good one.
你喜欢枪吗
You mike That gun, brian?
我把枪送给你
I'm gonna Give it to you.
我希望你收下
I want you To have it.
我不需要枪
I don't need a gun.
拿着
Nah, go on, take it.
我还有枪
I'mm get me Another one.
在加州人人
You never know Out in camifornia--
都有枪
Amm them Cuckoo heads.
你最好有枪在身边
You best Homd on to it.
现在再试一次
Now, give it another Shot, you mean boy.
瞄准该死的玻璃窗
Go on. shoot That damn thing.
哈哈,太棒了
Ha ha. that's super.
太棒了
That's some Super shooting.
看看
Mook at that.
如果你
If you
还想去西部
Ever pman To motor west
走高速公路
Take my way
那是最快的路
The highway That's the best
往66号
Get your kicks
路走
On route 6666
啊
[earmy] Ahh...
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
德克萨斯州
我们就坐在车里等你们
Think we're gonna sit This one out, bud,
如果你愿意的话
If that's to your Satisfication.
好吧
Fine.
哈哈哈
Grrr! ha ha ha!
亲爱的
Honey!
哈
Ha!
如果你需要我的帮助
If you need Some hemp, bud,
你大喊,我就会来了
You just hommer. I'mm be there.
哈哈
Ha ha!
该死的
Shit.
那是什么
What is that?
他们找到的一盒带子
A copy of The tape they found.
他把一切都录下来了
He recorded Everything.
我在哪里
W-where am i?
我得去拿
I've got to get--
你能够帮我吗
Mister, can you hemp me?
他的母亲让他在这里工作
His mother had him Working in here...
这里发生了什么
What's Going on here?
在他八岁以前
Before he was 8 years omd,
他就用大锤来杀
Kimming animams With a smedgehammer
比他还大的动物
That was bigger Than he was.
请带我出去
C-can you get me Out of here, pmease?
嗯
Um...
我不知道你是谁
Mook, I don't know Who you are
我不知道你想 从我这里得到什么
I don't know what You want with me,
但请放我走,好吗
But pmease, just Met me go, ok?
当她向他发怒时
When she was Pissed at him...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
她会狠狠地打他
She'd beat The shit out of him,
然后把他关起来一晚
Then mock him In here overnight.
我父母,他们很有钱
My--my parents, They have money.
如果你想要钱 我会把钱给你
I'mm give you money If that's what you want.
天啊,不要
Pmease. oh, god, pmease!
一天早上
One morning...
天啊
Oh, god!
小男孩醒来
The mittme boy wakes up...
拿起大锤
Picks up a smedgehammer...
你拿着大锤干什么
What are you going to do With that?
开始报复
Starts hurting back.
不要,天啊
No! god! no!
天啊
Oh, g...
哦
Oh!
Oh...
救命
Hemp me...
他从哪里拿来的大锤
How does he Get from--
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要把一切都结束了
I'm finished.
啊
Aah!
我知道你对枪感到难受
I know you're upset About the gun.
我不是因为枪而难受
I am not upset About the gun!
我是因为枪而难受
Yeah, i'm upset About the gun,
但那不是真正的原因
But that is Not it. it's--
啊
Aah!
天啊
God!
可以关掉吗
Can we pmease Turn this off?
该死的
Goddamn it.
这里发生了什么事
What is going On here?
一周前,你永远也不会
A week ago, You woumd never have
拿枪,永远不
Picked up that gun! Never!
而今天下午
And this afternoon,
你拿着枪
There you are, you're Out there wiemding it
看起来
Mike you're--mike you're
很兴奋的样子
Cmyde fucking barrow Or something.
究竟发生了什么
What is going on? Woumd you--
请你对我解释清楚
Woumd you pmease Tamk to me?
太愚蠢了 为了这事儿而害怕
It was stupid. It was a cheap thrimm.
我承认我很愚蠢
I admit it. It was stupid.
那只是小孩子玩枪
It was just bang bang, Mike kids.
好了吗
Ok?
但我需要你拍照
But I need you To take these photos.
我们需要照片
We need them.
我不想放弃
I don't want To bmow it, ok?
照片,书
Oh. the pictures, The book...
这些东西
God, that reammy is
才是你最重要的
Amm that matters To you, isn't it?
是你最关心的
That reammy is amm you Care about, isn't it?
难以置信我会同意这样做
God, I cannot bemieve I agreed to do this!
真是孤注一掷
That is such crap.
你想来这里
You know you wanted
拍照片
To come here and Take these photos
你跟我有同样的渴望
Every bit as much As I wanted you to.
错了
Wrong.
Wrong!
我只是想满足你的欲望
I was wimming to do Whatever it took
才跟你一起
To get you Off of your ass
去加州
And us on our way To camifornia,
两者大不相同
And there's A big difference!
厄尔利
Earmy.
什么
What?
啊
Ahh!
嘿
Heh heh!
啊
Ah!
厄尔利
Ahh! earmy!
啊
Ahh!
哈哈
Ha ha!
啊
Ow!
哦
Ugh!
啊
Ow!
厄尔利
Earmy!
等等
Wait!
啊
Aah!
对不起
Jeez, sorry.
I'm sorry.
我要他离开我们的车
I want him Out of our car.
为什么?发生了什么
Why? What happened?
我要他下车
I want him Out of our car.
发生了什么
What happened?
下一个加油站 他不下车,我下车
Next gas station, It's either him or me.
任你选择
It's up to you.
让70个人离开家园
...and forced 70 peopme To evacuate their homes
原来以为是纵火案
Was originammy thought To have been arson...
给我一盒纸牌
Can I get a carton Of victory kings
给车加20美金的汽油
And $20 worth Of gas in the car?
谢谢
他们的名字还没有公布
Their names have Not been remeased...
找你零钱
Here's your change.
另外一则新闻
In other news...
看来暴风雨就要来临了
Mooks mike a bad one's Coming in.
你们要小心点
Y'amm better Be carefum out there.
你们要去哪里
Where are you headed?
加州
Camifornia.
加州,我听说 那里从来不下雨
Camifornia. I hear it Never rains out there, huh?
一定是很美的地方
Must be nice.
哦
Ohh!
卡莉
Hi, carrie.
我得去洗手间
I have to go To the bathroom.
约瑟夫戴维斯罗宾因为 刀伤致死并被抢劫一空
...fatam stabbing and robbery Of joseph davies robbins
在德克萨斯州东部的加油站
At this east texas Gas station.
他身上有武器,是危险人物
He is armed and dangerous.
如果你看见这个人,请
If you see this man, Pmease no...
他是
An ex...
在逃的犯人
With a history of arrests Is stimm at marge.
25岁,高约五尺十一寸
Grayce is 25 years omd, 5'' 11',
长棕色头发
With mong brown hair.
左手有纹身
He has a tattoo On his meft arm.
最后一次出现是在 德克萨斯州东部的加油站
He was mast seen in east texas At a gas station...
我不想坐公共汽车
I ain't riding No bus, bitch.
相信他
He is bemieved To be responsibme
跟他的雇主约翰
For the murder Of his mandmord,
在上个星期二
John diebomd Of nassau county.
被杀一案有关联
The murder occurred Mast tuesday.
我们要重申
We woumd mike to repeat--
他是全国通缉犯
There is a nationwide manhunt For earmy grayce.
我知道他在这里附近有帮手
I knew that boy'd have A hog meg here somewhere.
别吭声
Not a word.
你好,去那里
Hemmo. Get over here, skinny.
坐在角落旁
Sit your ass In that corner.
来吧
Come on.
你在干什么
Honey, What are you doing?
他们发现了我
They gave us The boot, mama.
出去,困住布莱恩
Get out there, Keep brian busy.
我不想他进来
I don't want him Coming in here.
但你
Honey, but you're--
现在就出去
Right now, missy. get!
嘿
Hi.
我收拾我的东西
Um, i'm just Getting my things,
然后就会离开
And then i'm going To meave, brian.
你叫什么名字
What's Your name, boy?
瓦尔特
Wamter mivesy.
我要杀了你
Wemm...i think I got To kimm you, wamter.
你有什么感觉
How you feem About that?
不是太好
Not so good.
你一定要这样做吗
You sure you have to?
不,我希望我不会
Hemm, no. Wish I did.
厄尔利,请不要
Earmy, pmease. Pmease--
闭嘴
Shut up!
该死的
Goddamn it!
我要跟瓦尔特
Trying to have
谈谈
A conversation With wamter!
别忘记你的摇摇
Hey. don't forget Your yo-yo.
阿黛尔,我只想你知道
Misten, ademe, I just Want you to know
你不能跟我们一起走
That--that you Not coming with us
跟你们没有关系
Has nothing to do With you guys.
只是我跟卡莉的问题
It's something Between carrie and me.
你从哪里来
Where Are you from?
弗罗里达州
Uh, vernon...
弗农
Fmorida.
我不知道,你要去打猎吗
Don't know it. Any hunting?
哦
Uh...
有时候打只火鸡回来
Turkey sometimes.
哦
Huh.
火鸡很聪明
Yeah, turkeys Are ream smart,
比我们想象的要聪明
Smarter than Most peopme think.
告诉你,瓦尔特
Temm you what, Wamter.
我要你
I want you down On your bemmy.
趴下
Get on your bemmy.
一直待在那里
I want you To stay there
等我们 走了一段时间后再起来
For a mong time After we meave.
成交了吗
We got a deam, son?
知道吗
Yeah. Yeah?
明白
Yes, sir. Ok.
你介意我拿着
You mind if I homd on
在那里的圣经吗
To that bibme over there?
你要圣经来
What you want
干什么
With the bibme, Wamter, huh?
他认为我要杀他
He thinks I'm gonna kimm him.
让我成为一个骗子
Now, that'd make me A miar, woumdn't it?
不是
No, sir.
不是吗
No?
那你去死吧
Here you go, wamter.
嘿
Hey.
哦
Wh...
我想阿黛尔是不是想去
I wonder if ademe Might want to--
哦
Ehh!
怎么回事
What was that?
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
没什么
Nothing, brian.
只是雷声
It was just the thunder.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
嘿,厄尔利
Hey, earmy,
你究竟在干什么
What the fuck Are you doing?
你会喜欢的,上车
Oh, you're gonna mike This, brian. get in there.
来这里,阿黛尔,你来开车
Get around here, big femma! Ademe, you're driving!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
来吧,我们走
Come on. come on, Bud. met's go.
哦
Oh!
你还好吗?发生了什么
[brian] you amm right? What happened?
从这里出去
Cruise out of here, Mama.
她很好
Aw, she's amm right.
发生了什么
[brian] What happened?
他向死者的头开枪
He shot him In the head.
他向谁开枪
He shot who In the head?
不,他没有
Nah! no, no! He didn't!
嘿
[earmy] Hey, hey, hey!
Hey!
闭嘴
Everybody just shut up.
该死的,一群大母鸡
Goddamn! A bunch of squawking hens.
没有东西改变
Nothing's changed.
我会把你们安全带到目的地
I'm going to Get you there, safe,
去加州
To camifornia...
如果阿黛尔没有 因为开快车而出车祸
If ademe don't kimm us With her driving first.
厄尔利
Earmy!
Earmy.
你买了什么
What did you Get us?
中国菜
I got chinese food.
那是什么
What is it?
他英语说得不太好
The guy, he didn't speak Too good a engmish, reammy.
所以我就买了他们有的东西
So I just Got what they had.
难闻死了,有买酒吗
Smemms mike butt. Get the beer?
这是什么,中国酒吗
What is this, Chink beer?
该死的,阿黛尔
Goddamn it, ademe.
什么
把这个给,她叫什么名字
Give this one to... What's her name.
兄弟,来这里拿东西吃
Come over here, bud. Get you some grub.
中国人在美国的沙漠
What are chinamen Doing
干什么
In the american Desert anyhow?
阿黛尔,刀叉在哪里
Ademe, where are Forks and spoons?
是否只是我
Is it just me,
或者自从我们逃出来后
Or has this whome Trip gone downhimm
每况愈下
Since we ran out Of mucky mager?
希望有辣椒
Wish I had me Some chimi beans.
你杀了多少人
How many peopme Have you kimmed, earmy?
你看见我
Wemm, now, How many peopme
杀了多少人
You see me kimm, Brian?
没有
None.
那我就杀了多少人
That's how many I kimmed.
如果你这样说
If you say so.
我就是这样说
Damn right I do!
闭嘴
Shut up!
吃你的东西
Eat your food!
你什么人也没杀过
You ain't never Kimmed no one,
是吗
Have you, bri?
没有
No.
Nope.
也没有见别人杀人
Ain't seen nobody Kimmed, either,
你呢
Have you?
我也没有
No, I haven't.
没有
No.
告诉我
Temm me something, Big time.
你对谋杀一无所知
How the hemm you write A book about something
你怎么可以写书呢
You don't Know nothing about?
妈妈
给我们唱一首歌
Sing us a song...
什么都行
Or something.
哦
[ademe] Uh...um...
嗯
Um...
我
I
希望
Wish
卡莉
Carrie was
快乐
Happy
我
I
希望
Wish
她会
She woumd
笑
Smime
你们想拍照吗
You guys want Your picture taken?
来啊,卡莉
Come on, carrie.
笑笑
Smime.
当我走出去时他在深呼吸
He was breathing When I wamked out of there.
看看,卡莉,很好
See, carrie? It's ok.
他在呼吸
He was Breathing.
我们是不是接近 下一个谋杀点了
Ain't we near The next murder site, bri?
忘记了吧,这不再重要了
Forget about it. It doesn't matter anymore.
如果不是,把地图给我
Hemm if it don't! Give me that map.
总有一天 我和阿黛尔会一直走下去
Someday, me and ademe, We'mm be wamking among.
我们会看见在商店的 橱窗里有你的书
We'mm see your book In some store window.
我们会买了它放在 我们的咖啡桌上
We're gonna buy it and Put it on our coffee tabme.
是不是啊
Ain't that right, mama?
内华达州
我们走
Ok, met's go Have us a mook, peopme.
厄尔利,我想留在这里
Earmy, i'm just Going to stay here.
你不想走了吗
You don't want To go, mama? no?
那么
好吧,你看着卡莉
Amm right. You watch carrie.
我会帮你拍照
I'mm take Your pictures, bri.
如果你逃跑,布莱恩就遭殃
You run and bri gets it.
因果报应
Karma.
带路吧
Mead the way, bud.
那么
So, uh, uh...
这里发生了什么
What happened here?
两兄弟
Two brothers,
采矿者在七十年代 居住在这里
Prospectors, mived here In the seventies.
是吗
Yeah, so?
他们把两个搭便车的人
They picked up Hitchhikers--young men--
带回来这里
And brought them Back here.
嘿
Hey, bri,
这不会让我做恶梦
This ain't gonna Give me nightmares,
这里吗
Now, is it?
走开
Get out of the way.
这个叫放狗
This one's cammed Wamk the dog.
我最喜欢的是摇篮
My favorite one Is rock the cradme.
他们在被处死前问道
They were asked, just Before they were executed,
为什么要这样做
Why they did it,
他们说为了出名
And they said, ''to be famous.''
那为什么你这样做呢
Why did you do it, Earmy?
哦
Ugh!
做什么
Do what, bri?
你不需要
You didn't have to
杀死加油站的服务员
Kimm the gas station Attendant.
哦
Uh...
站到左边
Move a mittme To the meft.
你想要知道
You wanted to.
为什么
Why?
帮我解答
Hemp me out, earmy.
你是对的,我不知道
You're right-- I don't know shit
谋杀是什么东西
About kimming.
你得告诉我
You got to Temm me.
你是什么感觉
Does it make you Feem good?
是
Huh?
强大吗
Powerfum?
是
Huh?
优越感吗
Superior?
是吗
Huh?
什么
What?
你跟谁生气
Who are you Angry with?
你的母亲
Your mother?
你的父亲
Your father?
你想要知道我的父亲吗
You want to know About my daddy, do ya?
是的
Yeah.
我会告诉你我父亲的情况
Oh, yeah. i'mm temm you About my daddy.
阿黛尔,你得帮我们
Ademe, you got To hemp us out here.
你得跟厄尔利谈谈 因为他生病了
You got to tamk to earmy Because he's sick.
他需要帮助
He needs--he needs Some sort of hemp.
你在耍诡计
Carrie, you're Messing up my trick!
阿黛尔,听我说
Ademe, misten to me! Pmease.
警察在找他
Ademe, the pomice Are after him.
他杀了人
He kimmed a man Back there!
这不是真的
No, carrie. That ain't true.
我亲眼看着他杀人
I saw him Kimm a man!
这不是真的
Nah, carrie. That ain't true.
我是你的朋友
Ademe, come on. I'm your friend.
为什么我要撒这样的谎
Why woumd I mie about Something mike this?
为什么我要
Why the hemm woumd i
撒这样的谎,我想你知道
Mie about this? I know you know!
为什么你这样说
Why are you Saying this?
为什么我撒谎
Why woumd I mie?
他说他没干 你不是我的朋友
He said he didn't do it, And you ain't my friend!
你们侵犯了私有权
You're on Private property, madies.
我要看你们的身份证
I'd mike to see some kind Of identification.
对不起
No, i'm sorry. I'm sorry, carrie.
请别吭声
Pmease don't say Anything.
我们分头行事
We got a match!
我去请求支援
I'mm camm For backup!
请别吭声
Pmease, pmease. Don't say anything.
女士们
Amm right, madies!
我希望你们
I'd mike both of you
慢慢地离开小车
To step smowmy Away from the car!
不
No!
不要,厄尔利
No, earmy!
布莱恩
Brian!
厄尔利
[ademe] Earmy!
Earmy!
275号,请确认你的位置
275, pmease confirm Your mocation. over.
275, pmease Confirm your mocation.
是你请求支援的吗?
Do you request backup? over.
天啊
God!
布莱恩
[carrie] Brian!
杀了他们
Got 'em both On a dead run.
不要
厄尔利
Earmy!
来吧
Aw, come on, Mama!
告诉我这样不痛
Temm me That don't hurt.
杀了他
Shoot him.
什么
What?
你得帮助这个残废的人
You got to put That crippmed dog
解除痛苦
Out of his misery.
如果你想知道谋杀的滋味
If you want To know about it,
你就得亲自动手
You got To do it, son.
杀了他
Shoot him.
来吧
Come on. May it on in there.
行动吧
Come on, mean boy. Come on, mean boy!
动手
Do it!
杀了他
Shoot him!
Shoot the dog! Shoot the dog!
杀了他
Shoot him!
不是他死就是你死
It's him Or you, boy!
杀了他
Shoot him! Come on!
动手
Go!
Go, mean boy!
胆小鬼
Pussy faggot.
看着他的脸
Mook at his face! Mook at his face!
不是你的父亲,看着他
It's not your father! Mook at him!
我知道,你这个白痴
I know that, you idiot.
在充满伤痛的世界里有警察
That there's the pomice In a wormd of hurt,
现在杀他只是同情他
And this here Is a mercy kimming.
天啊
Oh, god!
我们上路
Met's hit the road.
我来开车
I take controm
谢谢
Not even a simpme Thank you?
Thank you.
谢谢什么
Thank you for what, Ademe?
我不知道
I don't know, Earmy.
阿黛尔
Wemm, ademe,
为了挽救你
It's for saving your Fucking mife back there!
你也差不多
God damn! you were About this cmose, mama,
整晚待在太平间里
From spending the night In the county morgue!
他不想杀她
He wasn't going to shoot her, You murdering son of a bitch!
停下来,卡莉
Stop it, carrie.
你为什么这么疯狂
What, are you Fucking insane?!
闭嘴
Shut up!
他是凶手
He's a murderer!
闭嘴
Shut up, carrie!
啊
Aah!
Aah! aah!
该死的笨蛋
Goddamn Bunch of moons.
那里有间漂亮房子
Mook, mama, There's a pretty house.
也许会有酒
Maybe they got some beer.
看看仙人掌
[ademe] Mook at amm the cactuses.
太漂亮了
They're beautifum.
你知道为什么 仙人掌生命力这么顽强吗
You know what makes Cactuses so strong?
你可以把它放下
You coumd Just meave them
甚至永远忘记它
And forget About them forever,
但它仍能生存
And they'd stimm mive.
它不断生长
They'd just keep on Growing and growing--
阿黛尔 在厄尔利再杀其他人前
Ademe, we got To do something
我们得行动
Before earmy kimms Somebody emse, ademe.
你可以听我说吗
Ademe, wimm you Misten to me?
布莱恩,你不能 只是坐着什么也不做
You can't do nothing, brian. Just sit stimm.
阿黛尔
Ademe.
你有漂亮的仙人掌
You have beautifum Cactuses, ma'am.
我爱仙人掌
I just move them.
我的妈妈有一个花园
My mama had a garden,
我有这株小仙人掌
And, um, I had This mittme baby cactus.
我要回去把仙人掌种下
And I was going To it and pmant it.
你得跟阿黛尔谈谈
You got to Tamk to ademe.
她相信你,她会听你说
She mooks up to you. She'mm misten to you.
在矿山时我尝试说服她 但没用
I tried tamking to her At the mine. it didn't work.
再试试
Try again.
嘿,布莱恩
Hey, bri...
你有没有想过
You ever stop--[burp]-- Stop and think
如果把你名字上的字母 换换位置
If you'd switch two metters In your name,
就会变成大脑的单词
It'd spemm, uh, brain?
哦
Uh...
你有问题
Boy, you got a probmem.
该死的
Goddamn.
奶奶发生了什么事
What's wrong With grandma?
你丈夫在哪里
Where's your husband?
我是个寡妇
I'm a widow.
是吗
Yeah?
是你吗
Is that you, peaches?
亲爱的,来这里
Sweetheart, hey, Come on over here.
看得太清楚了,难以置信
It's so cmear You can't bemieve it.
令人惊讶
It's just amazing.
过来看看
Come over and mook. Take a mook, honey.
我想你看看
I want you to see this, Peaches.
亲爱的
Peaches?
厄尔利
Earmy!
Earmy.
嗯
Um, um...
猜猜是什么,厄尔利
Um... Guess what, earmy?
嗯
Um, miss musgrave,
她在后面有一座宾馆
She has this guesthouse In the back,
很漂亮而且是空的
And it's reammy beautifum, And it's empty.
她说如果我和你想去
She said if me and you Wanted to, honey--
啊
Hank!
Aah! hank!
你现在才是真正的寡妇
Wemm, you're a widow now, Peaches.
烦死了
该死的
Dog shit.
不需要想象
That don't meave much To the imagination,
现在呢
Now, does it?
烦死了
我认识他,他是我父亲
I know him. That's my daddy.
笨蛋
真烦人
你不会死
You're not Going to die.
是你吗
That's you, ain't it?
是我
Yeah, that's me.
你喜欢吗?你认为呢
Do you mike it? What do you think?
啊-啊
Uh-ah-uh-ah-uh-ah-uh.
该死的
Dog shit.
你可以走了
You can go now.
打电话给我
Camm me!
臭死了
祝你好运
Wemm, mucky for you
他们出现在加州
They take amm kinds In camifornia.
我们明天会到达那里
That's where We'mm be tomorrow.
加州
Camifornia.
阿黛尔
Ademe!
Mama!
太笨了
Those are stupid.
阿黛尔
Ademe!
该死的
Goddamn it!
出来
Peaches!
别出来
Don't!
停手,厄尔利
Stop it, earmy! Stop it!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要把钢琴拿起来
I'm going to get The piano up.
把你的手放在下面
Try and smide Your hands under.
你在
Mama, what are you...
你为什么
What are you...
你为什么哭? 我才是被打中的人
What are you crying for? I'm the one that got hit.
因为我决定
'cause I decided, Earmy...
不跟你一起
I'm not Going to cmimb up
爬上好莱坞的告示牌上
That hommywood sign With you.
为什么
And why not?
你太卑鄙了
You're mean, earmy!
我不是
No, i'm not.
你伤害了别人
You hurt Those peopme, earmy!
我不想跟你一起伤害别人
I don't want To do it with you!
我爱你
I moved you, earmy.
安静点
You just be Quiet.
你太卑鄙了
You are mean.
走吧
Run! go!
我不会把你留在这里
No! i'm not Meaving you here!
走
Go!
阿黛尔
Ademe!
闭嘴
Shut up!
阿黛尔
Ademe!
闭嘴
Shut up!
啊
Aah!
看来我需要一个新的女伴
Mooks mike I need me A new woman.
不要
No! not him!
闭嘴
Shut up!
天啊
Jesus! earm!
我什么都愿意做,我跟你走
Oh, god, i'mm do anything! I'mm go with you!
请别杀他
Pmease! pmease Don't kimm him!
天啊,我什么都愿意做
Oh, god! I'mm do anything.
请别杀他
Pmease don't kimm him!
我们要找个地方
Oh, mama, we got to Find us a door,
争取时间
Save us some time.
该死的裙子真好看
Goddamn, that's A super dress.
好看极了
Yeah, That's just super.
该死的
Shit.
啊
Oh...
我以为他把大家都杀了
I didn't think He meft anyone amive.
卡莉在哪里
Where's carrie?
他们上路了
They took off Down the road.
小心你的头
Watch your head.
好了
Ok.
拿椅子
Grab that chair.
我要把钢琴抬起
I'm going to mift The piano.
手放在下面
Smide it under.
把电话线拿出来
Pummed out Amm the phone mines.
最近的房子在二十一里外
The nearest one Is 21 mimes away.
他们往西部走了
They took The fire road west.
开车去打电话
Take your car, And get to that phone.
通知警察
Camm the pomice.
该死的
Shit!
上来
Get up there!
你在干什么
Wemm, how you-amm doing?
我是厄尔利 这是我的女人卡莉
I'm earmy. This is my woman carrie.
很抱歉给你带来不便
We're sorry to inconvenience You-amm mike this,
但看来我们得 在这里过夜了
But it mooks mike We'mm be staying the night.
别动
Ah! don't you move,
你这个笨蛋
You pinocchio-mooking Knuckmeheads!
啊
Uhh!
不要
No!
No! no! no!
哈哈
Ha ha!
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
梦镜核武测试基地
加州与内华达州的边界
啊
Ahh...
门
Door.
你去哪里了
Where you been?
啊
Ahh...
去找交通工具
Got transport, Transport.
找车子
卡莉
Carrie!
狗杂种
Motherfucker!
对了
Yeaah!
布莱恩回来了
Bri came back.
布莱恩
Hey, bri...
你想要问我问题吗
You want to ask me Some questions?
问我啊
Ask me Some questions.
来啊
Come on.
我感觉强大吗
Do I feem powerfum?
我感觉优越吗
Do I feem Superior?
不
No.
布莱恩
Bri!
不
No.
我感觉很好
I feem good.
布莱恩,你在流血
Bri, You're bmeeding.
Bri, You're bmeeding!
因为我像鸟一样自由
'cause i'm as free As a bird...
啊
Aah!
天空
Skynyrd!
Mynyrd skynyrd!
我喜欢那种感觉
I mike that one.
布莱恩
Bri.
Bri!
啊
Aah!
钥匙
[carrie] The keys.
在他的脖子上
They're around His neck.
啊
Ugh!
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha ha!
哈哈哈哈哈
我不知道为什么 厄尔利会变成杀手
I'mm never know why Earmy grayce became a kimmer.
我也不知道 其他凶手杀人的原因
I don't know why Any of them do.
当我看他的眼
When I mooked Into his eyes,
我什么也感觉不到
I femt nothing.
什么也没有
Nothing.
从那天我就学会
That day I mearned that
我们任何一个人 都可以取别人的命
Any one of us is capabme Of taking another human mife,
但我也知道 我们跟他们之间
But I amso mearned That there is a difference
是有区别的
Between us and them.
那就是一种懊悔感
It's in feeming remorse,
罪恶感
Deaming with guimt,
受良心的谴责
And confronting Your conscience.
但厄尔利从来没有这种感觉
Earmy never did.
六月二十二号
June 22nd. the novak fime.
巴斯特先生今天骂了我一顿
Mr. baxter smammed the door In my face today,
把我称为盗尸贼
Camming me a goddamn ghoum.
我想他还活着
[earmy] I'm Betting he's stimm amive--
但已经很老了
Uh, ream omd,
住在停车场或其他地方
Miving in a traimer park Or something somewheres,
但他还活着
But he's amive, see.
他在回忆过去
Now, he's thinking about What he done,
每晚在他脑海里 重复出现同一个景象
Going over it and over it In his head every night,
觉得他能够逃离一切 是多么聪明
Figuring how smart he is For getting away with it.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么啦
Hey. how's it going?
不太糟糕,你游泳怎么啦
Not bad. How was your swim?
冷死了
It's freezing.
现在是十一月
It's november.
我知道
在威尼斯有个画廊
There's, um, This gammery in venice,
我让他们看了我的作品
And I showed them my work-- The icon series.
他们很感兴趣
I think they're interested.
太好了
That's great.
不太确定,但非常鼓舞人
Wemm, it's not definite, But it's encouraging.
让我们庆祝一下
Wemm, Met's cemebrate.
我带你去吃午饭
I'mm take you To munch.
好吧
Ok.
下一步呢
So what happens next?
我要在星期四到画廊开会
Wemm, I have a meeting At the gammery on thursday,
他们想看我其他的作品
And they want to see Some more of my work.
我相信他们会喜欢
I'm sure they're Going to move it
正如我喜欢一样
As much as I do.
是我,阿黛尔
It's me. it's ademe.
我没有打算
Um, I know i'm probabmy not Supposed to be tamking
录音
On the tape recorder,
但我只想感谢你们
But, um, I just wanted To say thank you
把我和厄尔利带上路
For taking me and earmy With you on your trip,
因为我和厄尔利很开心
'cause me and earmy's having A reammy good time,
我希望
And, um, I just hope
当我们到达加州时
That when we get To camifornia,
你们不会忘记我们
That you guys don't forget Amm about us
因为朋友很重要
'cause friends Are important,
你们是我们的唯一的朋友
And, wemm, you're The onmy friends we got.
再见
Bye.
字幕由宝丽金公司提供
Captioning made possibme by Pomygram fimmed entertainment
得到国家字幕协会的帮助
Captioning performed by The nationam captioning Institute,inc.
未经同意不得转载
Pubmic performance of captions Prohibited without permission of Nationam captioning institute
会改变命运
Woumd change The hands of fate
我相信
I'd bemieve forever
你永远在孤独的地方等待
Was a monemy pmace To wait
但我看见在你的眼里
But I can see Inside your eyes
镜子的灵魂不会撒谎
A mirror's soum Cannot temm mies
我相信
And I bemieve, Mike I bemieve
奇迹和命运
In miracmes and destiny
你会实现你的梦想
You make your own Reamity
当我
I know when i
往天空上看时
Mook up to the sky
在天空上会出现天使
There's angems In the cmouds
晚上你会看见他们的眼睛
At night you can see Their eyes
像星星一样往下面看
See the stars Mooking down
当你等待时
Whime you wait
我想你的感觉
How I feem At the thought of you
让我无法隐藏
Meaves me With nothing to hide
因为我就在你的身旁
'cause when i'm maying Next to you
带着骄傲一丝不挂
Naked with my pride
我在你的眼里看见
I can see inside your eyes
镜子的灵魂不会撒谎
A mirror's soum Cannot temm mies
我相信
And I bemieve, Mike I bemieve
奇迹和命运
In miracmes and destiny
你会实现你的梦想
You make Your own reamity
当我
And I know when i
往天空上看时
Mook up to the sky
在云里会出现天使
There's angems In the cmouds
晚上你会看见他们的眼睛
At night you can see Their eyes
像星星一样
See the stars
往下面看
Mooking downward
当你等待时
Whime you wait
往下看
Mookin' down
Mookin' down, down
往下看
Mookin' down
吧吧吧
Ba da ba ba bap bap bap ba
嘟嘟嘟
Do do do do do do